♪♪～
Houkai no shinfonii ga narihibiite
Furu ame wa maru de namida no neiro
Kizuite
Sono me wa tagai wo mitomeru tame
Sono koe wa omoi wo tsutaeru tame
Sono te wa daiji na hito to tsunagu tame ni aru
Kono uta ga kikoeteru
inochi aru subete no mono yo
Shinjitsu wa anata no mune no naka ni aru
Arashi no umi wo yuku toki mo
Keshite okusuru koto no nai tsuyosa wo
Kureru kara
Mana will be reborn by devouring Inori.
（涯）いのりを糧に
真名が復活する。→
Our lost Eve...
失われた　俺たちのイヴが。
（涯）一足　遅かったな　集。
You just missed her, Shu.
（集）そんな…！
No...
Prayer
（アルゴ）いったい　何なんだよ！？
この光は！
What the hell is this light?
Something's starting, that much is for sure.
（春夏）何かが始まっている！
それは間違いないわ。
（アルゴ）チェッ！　分かった。
ここは　俺たちで　しのぐ。→
Okay. We'll hold the fort here.
あんただけでも
早く　上に行ってくれ！
You hurry up to the top, even if we can't join you!
[無線]（アルゴ）綾瀬！　援護だ！
（綾瀬）「了解！　だけど…」
Ayase, you're backup!
Got it! But...
You've given me all kinds of hell...
but this time will be different!
（ダリル）「散々　やってくれたよね。でも　今度は違うよ！」
（ダリル）このゲシュペンストは！
（綾瀬）あっ！
Because of Gespenst here!
（綾瀬）「えい！」→
「だぁぁぁ！」
Tsugumi, you still can't get control back?
（四分儀）鶫。
まだ　取り返せないのですか？
（鶫）急に　防壁が
厚くなったのよ！→
Their defenses got beefed up all of a sudden!
These things are like zombies!
The more I kill, the more show up!
消しても消しても
ゾンビみたいに！
（四分儀）鶫と互角…。
あっ！→
Someone's fighting on par with Tsugumi?
研二…。　あなたですか。
Kenji...
So it's you?
（真名）ふぁー。
おはよう　トリトン。
Morning, Triton.
目覚めたか　真名。
Mana, you're awake.
うん。
Mm-hmm...
集！→
Shu!
I'm so happy!
うれしい！→
You came for me!
来てくれたのね！
大変だったのよ。
Your big sister had a hard time, you know.
お姉ちゃんの邪魔をする
すっごい嫌な女がいたの。→
There was this awful girl
who kept getting in my way.
でも　もう大丈夫。
そいつ　すりつぶして→
But it's okay now. I ground
her up and made this body mine.
この体　お姉ちゃんのものに
できたから。→
Really, she had some nerve
for a man-made monster.
だいたい　生意気なのよ。
つくられた化け物のくせに。
Stop it!
やめろ！
あっ！　集…。
Shu?
いのりは　化け物なんかじゃない！
Inori's no monster! She cried for me!
彼女は
僕のために泣いてくれたんだ。
姿と声は同じだけど
君とは違う！
Her face and her voice may be
the same, but she's different from you!
彼女は人間だ！
She's a human!
（真名）ひどいわ　集。→
You're so mean, Shu.
お姉ちゃんは
あなたのこと大好きなのに。→
Your big sister loves you...
体が散り散りになっても
愛してたのに…。→
I loved you even after my body was torn apart...
And yet... you're still refusing me, aren't you, Shu?
なのに　また　私を拒むのね　集！
それくらいにしろ。
That's enough.
涯…。
Gai!
あとは　俺に任せるんだ。
Just leave the rest to me.
♪♪～
（真名）お姉ちゃんは
傷ついたわ　集。→
I was very hurt, Shu.
人を傷つけた人は　同じくらい
自分も傷つけられることを→
You know, when you hurt other people,
you have to be prepared to get just as hurt.
覚悟しなくちゃいけないのよ。
謝っても
許してあげないんだから。
Even if you apologize,
I'm not going to forgive you.
♪♪～
これは…！
What's?!
♪♪～
（亞里沙）始まったのね　涯。
It's begun, hasn't it, Gai?
あっ！
（兵士たち）おぉ…！
（司令官）何が起こっている！？
（管制官）２４区から→
What's happening?!
There's genomic resonance coming from Ward 24
ロストクリスマスを　はるかに上回る
高出力のゲノム共鳴が！
at output values that make
Lost Christmas look like nothing!
（管制官）その影響で　エンドレイヴの
遠隔共鳴システムにも干渉が！
It's interfering with the Endlaves'
remote-resonance systems!
♪♪～
これは…。
What's?
The Fourth Apocalypse has begun.
始まったのさ　四度目の黙示録。
この星の　命の進化と淘汰が。
The evolution and selection of life on this planet!
Yahiro!
谷尋！
《脆弱な肉体を捨て→
They will shed their frail physical bodies
結晶の中に
永遠の思考を獲得する》
and gain eternal thought within the crystal.
《それが　次なるステージ》
That is the next stage.
《ヴォイドは前触れだったのさ！
心が物質となる新たな世界の》
The Voids were the harbingers... of the
new world, where mind becomes matter!
（ダリル）「ハハハハ！　アハハハ！」
This is what you get for coming
at me with conventional arms!
通常兵装なんかで来るからだよ！
Watch out, I'm gonna crush you!
（ダリル）「ほらほら
つぶしちゃうよ！」
くっ！
やらせるかーっ！！
Oh no you don't!
なめんな　この野郎！
綾瀬。　有線接続だ！
Don't underestimate us, you punk!
Ayase! Use the wired connection!
あ…！
鶫。　回避プログラムを！
鶫！？
Tsugumi! We need an evasive program!
Tsugumi?
（ダリル）「女ぁぁ！」
ああっ！
てめえ！！
Bastard!
What?!
何！？　あっ！
（ローワン）ダリル少尉！
ヴォイドゲノムエミュレーターは試作段階なんだ。
Lieutenant! The Void Genom
Emulator is still in its trial phase!
Don't overdo it!
[無線]（ローワン）使い過ぎるな！
（ダリル）何　言ってんの。
You've got to be kidding.
There's no way in hell I'll stop...
やつら全員　ぶち殺すまで
やめるわけないだろ！！
...until I kill every last one!
Souta!
颯太！
涯！　あのとき　六本木の地下で
君は　真名を救うと言った！
Gai!
That day underground in Roppongi,
you said you'd save Mana!
救うために　あのとき
自分を刺せと言った！
You told me to stab you to save her!
なのに
どうして　こうなるんだよ！？
So why did things turn out like this?!
You wouldn't understand, Shu!
お前には分からない　集！
うっ…！
You're always being chosen,
and you just keep abdicating...
常に選ばれ　それを
勝手に手放してきた　お前には→
You'd never understand!
絶対に分からない！！
はあぁぁ！！
うあっ！
（茎道）どうだ？　クロス。→
How do you like this, Kurosu?
The daughter you tried to
save is about to end the world.
お前が救おうとした娘が
世界を終わらせるぞ。→
俺の勝ちだ。
I win.
Is that what you dragged the world...
dragged Shu into this for?
（春夏）そのために　世界を…。
集を巻き込んだの？
（茎道）あえて否定はしない。→
I won't deny it.
俺を撃つか？　春夏。
Are you going to shoot me, Haruka?
（亞里沙）《通すわけにいかない！
守り抜いてみせる　あの人を！》
I can't let them through.
I swear I'll protect him to the end!
何て　しつこい…！→
Talk about persistent!
ハッ！　ああっ！
駄目！　このままじゃ…！
No! At this rate...
Tsugumi.
（四分儀）「鶫。　私が合図するまで
持たせてください」→
Hold out until I give you the signal.
You can do it, can't you?
「できますね？」
（鶫）誰に言ってんの！
Who do you think you're talking to?
（うめき声）
昔のお前になら　真名を…。
アダムの地位を譲ってもよかった。
I wouldn't have minded yielding Mana...
yielding the status of Adam to the old you.
くっ…！
だが→
But the man you are now isn't worth it.
今のお前に　その価値はない。
死ね　集。
Die, Shu.
《体が重い…》
My body feels so heavy...
《これで終わりなのか？》
Is this where it ends?
While I still have everybody's Voids?!
《みんなのヴォイドを
抱えたまま…》
（いのり）諦めないで　集。
Don't give up, Shu.
（いのり）あなたの体は　まだ動く。
みんなが　集を待ってる。
Your body can still move.
Everyone's waiting for you.
ハッ！
お願い　みんな…。
Please, everyone...
私を使って。
...use me!
♪♪～
I'll never be loved by you again
何！？
What?!
Or needed by you again, either
あっ！
何が起こってるの？
What's happening?
And so here I am, all alone
（城戸）あっ。
研二。
チェックメートです。
Kenji. This is checkmate.
ヒヒッ！
≪（銃声）
僕に　命を預けて→
What did you say that day?
There are people who've put their lives
in my hands, who believe in me.
信じてくれている人がいるんだ。
僕は　まだ終われない。
必ず　いのりを取り戻す！
I can't end yet.
Words that'll never be heard flutter in the air
I'm getting Inori back, no matter what!
（茎道）うっ…！
（春夏）あっ。
♪♪～
Even though I know better,
I can't help making another
Hopeless wish today
（四分儀）「今です！」
Now.
綾姉　お待たせ！
Sorry to keep you waiting, Aya!
Here I go!
（綾瀬）「行くわよ！」
[無線]（鶫）リモートの制御は任せて！
Leave the remote control to me!
涯…。
邪魔をするなら→
Gai. If you're going to get in my way,
僕は　全力で　君を倒す！
I'll use everything in my power to take you down!
Yes, hold me tight as you can and don't let go
That voice... So you are here, runt!
その声…。　やっぱ　いるんじゃんかちんちくりん！
- Tsugumi!
- Aye!
（綾瀬）「鶫！」
[無線]（鶫）アイ！
I want to be in your arms
何！？
What?!
（綾瀬）「だぁぁぁ！！」
お前らをやれば
僕は　僕でいられるんだ。
If I kill you guys, I can stay myself.
I can be Kill-'em-All Daryl!
We'll sleep with our foreheads pressed together
皆殺しのダリルでーっ！！
Can it! You're just a weakling!
お黙り！
あんたは　もやし子よ！
♪♪～
Inori...
いのり…！
うあぁぁぁぁ！！
No!
嫌ぁぁぁ！！
Did we do it?
やった…！
あっ。
♪♪～
兄さん！
Brother!
（茎道）結局　勝ったのは
俺でも　クロスでもない。→
In the end it wasn't me or Kurosu who won...
行け　春夏…。
Go, Haruka.
涯…！
Gai...
それでいい　集…。
That's good, Shu.
そういう　お前で…。
Stay the way you are right now.
Where am I?
ここは？
淘汰の収束点。
Selection's point of convergence.
黙示録の果ての世界だ。
It's the world that lies beyond the Apocalypse.
Gai...
涯…！
これが　ダアトの言う理想郷…。
This is what Daath speaks of as Shangri-La.
Everything on this planet will
become a memory encased in crystal.
この星の全ては→
結晶の中の思い出となるのさ。
Even me, the man they
set up as a "king," eventually.
王などと祭り上げられた俺も
やがては…。
I was always afraid of being selected out.
俺は　ずっと
淘汰されることを　恐れていた。
だからこそ　あらがい→
That's precisely why I resisted
selection, and wanted Eve... Mana.
イヴを…。
真名を欲した。
That day, when I was stabbed
by you underground in Roppongi,
あのとき
六本木の地下で　お前に刺されて→
I thought I could free Mana that way.
俺は　これで
真名を解放できると思った。
しかし　ダアトは…。
生物淘汰の意思は→
But Daath, the will of natural selection,
won't allow Mana to die.
真名に死を許さない。
たとえ　朽ちようと
再生させられるのさ。
Even if she perishes, she'll just
be brought back to life again.
There's only one way to free her:
解放するすべは　ただ１つ。
その役目を終わらせること。
to bring her role to an end.
だから　俺は賭けた。
So I gambled:
自ら魔王となり
アポカリプスを成就することに。
I bet on becoming a demon king
and bringing the Apocalypse about...
And I bet on you coming here.
そして　お前がやって来ることに。
俺の役目は　ここまでだ。
I've fulfilled my role.
涯！
Gai!
あとは　お前が　いのりを救え。
You do the rest... save Inori.
Shu...
集。
集…　自分を責めないで。
Shu...
Don't blame yourself.
私→
I got lots of feelings from you.
集に　たくさんの気持ちを
もらったよ。
全部…　集のおかげ…。
They're all thanks to you.
あっ…。
ねえ　集。
どこ…？
Hey, Shu... where are you?
集…。
Shu?
あっ…。
集。
Shu.
Stay with me forever, okay?
ずっと　そばにいてね？
私は　集の味方だから…。
I'm on your side, Shu.
Okay?
ねっ？
いのり。　一緒に行こう。
Inori... Let's leave together.
あっ…。
あっ？
♪♪～
（花音・谷尋）あっ。
（颯太）おい。　今…。
Hey, did we just...?
Yes, I just felt Ouma!
（花音）うん　感じたわ。
桜満君を。
（谷尋）集　お前…→
Shu, you... are you trying to
be some kind of savior now?!
救世主にでも　なるつもりかよ！？
えっ？
（亞里沙）うっ…！
（ダアト士官）ゲノム結晶体による
全フレーム構造が暴走中！→
The entire framework made of genom
crystallizations is going haywire!
間もなく　当施設は崩壊します！
This facility is about to collapse!
みんな…！
Guys...
Dr. Ouma! You're all right?
（倉知）桜満博士！
無事でしたか。
（ダリル）あんた…！
You...
（ローワン）生き直せるんなら
今度は　もっと　人に優しくしろ！
If you get to do life over again,
be nicer to people next time!
ホントは　いい子だったろ！
ダリル坊やは。
You were really a good kid
at heart, weren't you, Daryl?!
≪（銃声）
《みんなの心が
流れ込んでくる…》
The feelings in everyone's
hearts are flowing into me...
《思い出も…》
...and their memories...
Even the people who had bad will toward me...
《僕に悪意を向けた人だって→
...were born loved by somebody.
誰かに愛されて生まれたんだ…》
いのり…。
Inori...
取って。
Take this.
ハッ！
Inori!
いのり！
♪♪～
（綾瀬）待って！　集が　まだよ！
（アルゴ）分かってる！→
Wait! Shu's not out yet!
I know that!
だが　俺だって　お前たちを
死なせるわけには　いかねえ！
But I can't just let you die, either!
Shu!
集！！
♪♪～
≪（颯太）おう　谷尋！
Hiya, Yahiro!
（谷尋）早かったじゃないか。
Wow, you're early.
（颯太）仕事　忙しいの？
（谷尋）まあな。→
Busy at work?
Fairly. But I wrapped things up early today.
でも　今日は
早めに切り上げてきた。
ここ　構いませんか？
（綾瀬）どうぞ。
Would you mind if I sat here?
Go ahead.
（鶫）綾姉。
アールグレイで　よかった？
Earl Grey okay, Aya?
I'll never be loved by you again
You're so kind, Tsugumi.
優しいのね　鶫。
（鶫）今日だけはね。
Only for today.
もう　教員試験　近いんだから
帰ったら　また　鬼だよ。
Teaching exams are coming up,
so I'll be a demon again when we get home!
Or needed by you again, either
（谷尋）あいつは　まだ？
Isn't he here yet?
He'll come. He's been
really looking forward to it.
（綾瀬）来るわよ。
すっごく楽しみにしてたんだから。
And so here I am, all alone
Here he is!
（花音）あっ　来た！
（颯太）おっ！
みんなは久しぶりよね。
We haven't all seen each other in a while, huh?
What did you say that day?
みんな　お待たせ。
Sorry to keep you waiting, guys.
Words that'll never be heard flutter in the air
All right, to this year!
（颯太）それじゃ　今年も！
Cheers!
（一同）乾杯！
Even though I know better,
I can't help making another
♪♪～
Hopeless wish today
Keep holding my hand tight and don't let go
Tell me you'll stay with me
♪♪～
Your hand in mine was warm and kind